medscimonit.com 2019-03-31

# ISI - Privacy policy

In this privacy policy we explain how we collect and use your personal information. This privacy policy applies to all personal information we process about you when you publish with us, purchase or use our services, visit our websites, use our mobile applications or otherwise interact with us. Please click on the relevant section below for further information.

 **Who we are**

We are International Scientific Information, Inc., (ISI Inc.) an Open Access Publisher, with offices at 150 Broadhollow Rd., Melville, NY 11747, U.S.A.

ISI Inc., is responsible for collection and use of your personal data described in this Privacy Policy. We publish scholarly journals in the fields of bio-medical sciences.

We have determined our respective responsibilities for compliance with the obligations under applicable privacy legislation for processing your personal data in relation to our publications by means of an arrangement between us. In summary, we have arranged that if you want to exercise your rights, such as your right to access, correct, erase, restrict, object or port personal data or to withdraw your consent, or if you have any questions or complaints about the processing of your personal data, you can either contact us in accordance with ‘Your rights’ (please see below) or contact International Scientific Information Officer.

 **The types of personal data we process**

a) Name, title, gender, specialty, scientific interest/expertise in the form of MeSH (Medical Subject Headings) keywords, Institution and country of residence

b) Contact details, i.e.: email address and phone number (optionally). When you create a personal account, or register for a service, we may also record your sign in details and other information you fill out on your personal account or registration form.

c) information about your publication(s) and purchases

d) our communication with you. When you send us an email or chat with us online or via social media, we register your communication with us. We also register your communication preferences. When you call us, our customer support will register your questions or complaints in our database. We may also record telephone calls for training purposes or to prevent or combat fraud.

e) Information we collect when you use our websites. When you visit our websites, or use our mobile apps, we may register your IP address, browser type, operating system, referring website, web-browsing behavior and app use. We also collect information via cookies and similar technologies when you visit our websites or use our mobile apps. We may receive an automatic notification when you open our emails or click on a link in such emails.

f) Information in relation to social media. Depending on your social network settings we may receive information from your social network provider. For example, when you sign in for our services using a social network account, we may receive your social network profile including your contact details, interests and contacts. For more information on the personal data that we receive from your social network provider and how to change your settings, please check the website and privacy policy of your social network provider.

g) Information you choose to share with us. You may choose to share information with us, for example when you share your interests and preferences with us, leave a comment for us on Facebook, fill out a customer survey or submit an entry for a contest.

 **How we collect your data**

a) We collect data you provide to us. When you create an online account, register for one of our information programs, contact our customer support, subscribe to receive our emails or mobile push notifications, register for one of our events or participate in a promotional contest. 

b) When you use our website or mobile apps, we collect information via cookies and similar technologies. For more information please read our cookie policy on our websites or the mobile app you use. 

c) Some information we receive from public authorities or governmental organizations.

 **For which purposes we use your data**

4.1. To provide our services to you: 

a) to handle and process your manuscript submissions, 

b) to provide you an update on your publication statistics, 

c) to provide you update on any new manuscripts published in our journals that are related to your previous publication. 

d) to provide personalized offers like special discounts on manuscript processing fee, invitations

e) for statistical analysis 

4.2. To communicate with you. We use your contact details to communicate with you in relation to our services, to answer your questions or to handle your complaints. 

4.3. For record keeping and to comply with statutory obligations

 **Disclosing or sharing data with third parties**

a) For support services. We use third parties to provide our services, such as IT suppliers, bibliography indexing organizations, credit and charge card companies and anti-fraud / anti-plagiarism screening service providers or social network providers. All such third parties will be required to adequately safeguard your personal data and only process it in accordance with our instructions. Within ISI Inc., business activities are carried out (and business efficiencies are achieved) by processing or consolidating information (including personal data) in centralized databases and systems hosted on our servers.

 **Security and retention** ** **

a) ISI Inc., will take appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect your personal data against loss or unlawful use. 

b) Your personal data will be retained for as long as required for the purposes described in this privacy policy or in so far as such is necessary for compliance with statutory obligations and for solving any disputes. 

**Your rights**

a) Right to access. You may ask us whether or not we process any of your personal data and, if so, receive access to that data in the form of a copy. When complying with an access request, we will also provide you with additional information, such as the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned as well as any other information necessary for you to exercise the essence of this right. 

b) Right to rectification. You have the right to have your data rectified in case of inaccuracy or incompleteness. Upon request, we will correct inaccurate personal data about you and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, complete incomplete personal data, which may include the provision of a supplementary statement. 

c) Right to erasure. You also have the right to have your personal data erased, which means the deletion of your data by us and, where possible, any other controller to whom your data has previously been made public by us. Erasure of your personal data only finds place in certain cases, prescribed by law and listed under article 17 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). This includes situations where your personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the initial purposes for which they were processed as well as situations where they were processed unlawfully. Due to the way we maintain certain services, it may take some time before backup copies are erased. 

d) Right to restriction of processing. You have the right to obtain the restriction of the processing of your personal data, which means that we suspend the processing of your data for a certain period of time. Circumstances which may give rise to this right include situations where the accuracy of your personal data was contested but some time is needed for us to verify their (in)accuracy. This right does not prevent us from continuing to store your personal data. We will inform you before the restriction is lifted. 

e) Right to data portability. Your right to data portability entails that you may request us to provide you with your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and to have such data transmitted directly to another controller, where technically feasible. Upon request and where this is technically feasible we will transmit your personal data directly to the other controller. 

f) Right to object. You also have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, which means you may request us to no longer process your personal data. This only applies in case the ‘legitimate interests’ ground (including profiling) constitutes the legal basis for processing (see ‘Legal basis’). At any time and free of charge you can object to direct marketing purposes in case your personal data are processed for such purposes, which includes profiling purposes to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing. In case you exercise this right, we will no longer process your personal data for such purposes. 

g) You may withdraw your consent at any time. You may withdraw your consent at any time by following the specific instructions in relation to the processing for which you provided your consent. For example, you may withdraw consent, by clicking the unsubscribe link in the email, adjusting your communication preferences in your account. 

For more information on how you can withdraw your consent for cookies and similar technologies we use when you visit our websites or use our apps, please check the cookie policy on our website or in the app. There may be situations where we are entitled to deny or restrict your rights as described above. In any case, we will carefully assess whether such an exemption applies and inform you accordingly. We may, for example, deny your request for access when necessary to protect the rights and freedoms of other individuals or refuse to delete your personal data in case the processing of such data is necessary for compliance with legal obligations. The right to data portability, for example, does not apply in case the personal data was not provided by you or if we process the data not on the basis of your consent or for the performance of a contract. 

When you would like to exercise your rights, all you have to do is send your request to the

International Scientific Information, Inc., 

Privacy Office 

150 Broadhollow Rd., Ste.114 

Melville, NY 11747 U.S.A. 

email: [privacy.office@isi-science.com](mailto:privacy.office@isi-science.com)

**About this policy**

This privacy policy was most recently amended on 21 May 2018 and replaces earlier versions. We may amend this privacy policy from time to time and will notify you of any changes prior to these changes taking effect.
